GenomIQ Evidence Visualizer is a research-grade multi-agent assistant for genomic variant evidence review.
The demo starts inside Microsoft Foundry, where the GenomIQ agent is configured with clear research-only safety instructions.
A custom OpenAPI tool connects the Foundry agent to the local GenomIQ backend through a temporary demo endpoint.
The input is a synthetic, de-identified colorectal cancer research case containing BRAF V600E and a genomic coordinate.
The backend normalizes the variant input, runs MCP-style annotation, and queries NCBI/PubMed source interpretation paths.
The agent returns parsed variants, dbSNP IDs, PubMed evidence IDs, verification findings, and a generated report URL.
The interactive HTML report summarizes the top disease research hypotheses with confidence, evidence coverage, and claim status.
Evidence tabs show dbSNP and PubMed source metadata, while the reasoning tab exposes the multi-agent trace.
Safety checks verify citation format, annotation coverage, low-confidence claims, PHI/PII patterns, and export approval state.
The visual report is illustrative and deterministic. It is not a diagnosis tool and does not provide treatment recommendations.
The result is a cost-aware hackathon demo combining Microsoft Foundry Agents, OpenAPI tools, MCP, NCBI evidence, verification, and visualization.